import { RawGuitarData } from "./types/types";

export const rawData: RawGuitarData[] = [
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Squier Strat (modified)",
    brand: "Fender",
    year: "1999",
    imageFront: "punk-squier",
    imageBack: "punk-squier",
    history: "This was the first guitar I ever owned.  It came to me in high school as a gift from my parents.  I remember starting to fall in love with guitar music through alternative and grunge rock.  A friend's brother was into music during that time, as a guitarist and drummer.  Through him I was introduced to a local band called Guilt by Association, and theirs were the first shows I ever attended.  We saw them play at the Cobalt, a ratty 18-and-over venue in Canoga Park, and later on a much bigger stage at The Key Club in Hollywood.  This, along with the tail end of the grunge scene that was still making air time on the radio at the time, convinced me that I needed a guitar of my own.\n\nMy parents supported my sojourn into music and this guitar became the one that started me on my way.  With it, I took music classes at my high school, jammed with friends and even once (hah) with Sean de la Tour (Guilt by Association's rhythm guitarist), and had my first experience modifying guitar equipment.\n\nOut of the box, this was a non-standard Squier.  The first time I took it to the shop, the guitar tech (Randy at Sam Ash, where the guitar was purchased together with a tiny Fender bass amp) noted the flame maple neck with rosewood fretboard.  He pointed out that sometimes, ironically, the factory would run out of the cheap parts and have to throw really nice stuff on the Squiers at that time.  (I guess this might have been a Chinese factory thing, as this model was a made-in-China specimen.)  In any case, to this day, that neck contributes to this being one of my best-playing guitars.\n\nOver time, I wanted more of that punk/metal feel, so I got a Seymour Duncan single-slot, dual-coil pickup installed in the bridge position.  I also started in pretty heavy with the aesthetic mods, starting with an over-spray of model car paint I had left over form my remote control racing days.  I went for silver with a schmear of blue in an attempt to evoke the Earth under a silver background.  Even this intentionally slopped paint job is now laid over with a variety of stickers and decals from all throughout the many chapters of my life.  In keeping with the punk aesthetic of the guitar, when it came time for a new tuner and new potentiometer knobs, I specifically chose mismatched items to give it that disjointed vibe.  Still one of my favorite guitars."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "RG450",
    brand: "Ibanez",
    year: "1994",
    imageFront: "rg450",
    imageBack: "rg450",
    history: "This was my second guitar, and the first I ever paid for with my own money.  After my first guitar, a Fender Squier Strat, I wanted something a little fancier and a little nicer, and something that would better fit the type of playing I aspired to at the time.  I had been listening to a lot of hard rock and heavy metal, and my friend had been taking me to see a local band he knew playing shows in Hollywood.  They played some pretty hard rock, and I was mesmerized by the persona of the rhythm guitarist, who wore costumes and played - you guessed it - an Ibanez.  I got to meet the guy, Sean de la Tour of the band Guilt by Association, was in a class with him at school, and he even invited me to a jam session, and I got it into my head that I needed an Ibanez of my own.\n\nThis RG 450 was my first foray into \"grown-up\" guitars, and cost a pretty penny in its day.  It came with a premium, Ibanez-branded hard case, and had locking strings with a Floyd Rose floating bridge, lending it even more of a professional air.  I couldn't play it for crap at the time, but it came with me to college and was the guitar that I used to learn my first really challenging songs.  Most notably, I delved into some Opeth with this guitar.\n\nLater in life, this guitar spent some time neglected, and I even considered selling it for a time.  It was falling into disrepair and I didn't know how to take care of it properly.  More recently in life, however, I've learned a lot more about guitar maintenance, and with the help of my girlfriend's uncle, gave this guitar a complete overhaul, bringing it to near-new condition.  Because of this guitar I now know how to do a proper setup on a guitar with locking strings and a floating trem.  This guitar has also been one of the most underappreciated ones in my collection, over its career.  It plays amazingly when it's set up correctly.  Ibanez is famous for making guitars with fast necks for shredders, and it plays great under a light touch.  I have been the weak link in terms of what this guitar can do."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Handmade",
    brand: "Durazo",
    year: "2021",
    imageFront: "durazo",
    imageBack: "durazo",
    history: "I made friends with twin dudes when I returned to college late in life to chase a career change, and through them I met a friend who built guitars from near-scratch.  He even won contests with some of them, and was (very casually) tossing around the idea of making them a side gig.  I was so impressed at the time that I asked him if he would be interested in making one for me.  Together we went over my desired specifications.  I chose the shape, color, hardware, strings, which wood we'd use for the body, everything.  We sourced parts and raw materials online, and Mr Durazo got down to work.\n\nIn the end, it was a very expensive project, especially considering Mr Durazo's time, and ultimatley we weren't quite able to meet the specifications I had hoped for.  Unfortunately, this is not one of my favorite guitars, in part because the fit-and-finish and color were not a match for what I'd hoped for, and more importantly because the balance and geometry make it a bit awkward for me to play.  So while I'm happy to have had this project in my life, it hasn't seen a lot of play time in my hands."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Squier Strat",
    brand: "Fender",
    year: "2000",
    imageFront: "squier-strat",
    imageBack: "squier-strat",
    history: "This Squier was kind of a hand-me-down.  A girl I dated had it sitting in her dad's closet, disused, for 20 years.  She had gotten it as a gift in high school, hoping to learn to play, but never got around to it.  It sat and corroded until one day she gave it to me because she knew she was never going to use it.  The internal corrosion was bad enough that the whammy bar seized in the bridge and snapped at the threads, but luckily the electronics were all intact and the exterior was super clean.  I was also happy to have it because it is an exact copy of the first guitar I ever had, down to the color, making it a very interesting window into my guitar history.  It's really cool to be able to see my modified Squier side-by-side with an untouched original."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Slammer",
    brand: "Hamer",
    year: "80s-90s",
    imageFront: "slammer",
    imageBack: "slammer",
    history: "There was a brief period of time during which I thought I wanted to keep a cheap beater guitar around to keep in the office at work, lend to friends who wanted to learn guitar, etc.  It was right around that time that I went on a road trip to Santa Barbara, and on that road trip, my date suggested we visit some antique shops downtown.  In the moment, I had no thoughts of looking for guitars, but one of the shops had this Hamer on consignment, tucked away in a corner.  At the listed $150 I was hesitant, but my date went into haggle mode and got the price down to $100; the shop had to call the guitar's owner but it worked out.  The experience taught me a good deal about haggling in those kinds of situations, and also gave me the crackpot idea that I wanted to buy dirt-cheap guitars as souvenirs on trips from that point forward."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "CR-6",
    brand: "Schecter",
    year: "2021",
    imageFront: "cr-6",
    imageBack: "cr-6",
    history: "This was my first truly high-quality guitar.  I remember going into the Guitar Center in Sherman Oaks, looking to buy a beautiful, yellow, flame maple top PRS semi-hollow body that they had on the wall.  But while I was in there, I saw that they had this gorgeous CR-6 on a floor stand.  I was so taken by the undyed poplar burl top that I decided I wanted to try playing it to see if it was a nice guitar, or just for show.  I recall playing Minor Swing, a Django Reinhardt tune I was working on at the time, and having such a good time with it that I forgot to concentrate on the song, forgot to think about the guitar, and the joy of playing just spilled out of my fingers.  It was quite glorious!  The more I looked at the poplar top, the more I thought it looked like a museum piece, so pretty, so I forsook the PRS and bought the Schecter instead.\n\nI also remember putting my haggling skills to use on this one.  Being a floor model, it had a couple imperfections from being play tested and jostled about.  Pointing these out, I asked if they could take anyting off the price, and the dude talked his manager into giving me $40 off, which was most of the tax and made me happy.\n\nLater that night, I remember calling the store to talk to Edward, the guy who sold me the guitar.  I could tell in his voice he was afraid that I was another ornery customer calling to complain, but I was calling to thank him for his help, the price break, and the guitar, which I adored.  It seriously made his day."
  },
  {
    type: "Semi-hollow",
    model: "SE Custom 22 Semi-hollow",
    brand: "Paul Reed Smith",
    year: "2021",
    imageFront: "se-custom-22",
    imageBack: "se-custom-22",
    history: "I remember seeing this guitar on the wall at the Guitar Center in Sherman Oaks for the first time, and thinking to myself, why would anyone want that in yellow?  Then, weeks later, I remember the feeling of sitting at home remembering that yellow guitar and realizing that yes, *I* wanted it.  That golden yellow flame maple top with the single f-hole of the semi-hollow body design had burnt into my brain and wouldn't get out.  It didn't hurt that I had always, for over a decade, wanted a PRS in my collection because of the lovely blue one my friend Earl had.  When I finally worked up the courage to walk into the Guitar Center and buy it, it was still there, but there was a museum-quality Schecter on the floor that intercepted my affections, and I bought that instead.  The next time I went into that Guitar Center (for strings or whatever it was that I needed), the yellow PRS was gone, sold, so I figured the universe was telling me I just didn't need it after all.\n\nFast forward another few months, I was in the Guitar Center again, shopping for parts for my Frankenstein Squier.  Lo and behold, that same yellow PRS was back, now in the used section and for $300 off the original price.  Someone had eaten the depreciation off the top and left me with a mint PRS for a cut-rate price.  The universe really did want me to have this PRS!  It is probably my favorite guitar (though it does face stiff competition)."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "S561",
    brand: "Ibanez",
    year: "2022",
    imageFront: "s561",
    imageBack: "s561",
    history: "Guitar Center has a mailing list you can sign up for that is separate from their sale and product blasts.  I got just such an email one day in early 2023 advertising a free meet-and-greet and guitar clinic with guitar virtuoso Nita Strauss at the Hollywood Guitar Center.  It turned out that the clinic, such as it was, really consisted more of a plug for one of her albums and for her new signature Ibanez.  It was still a cool event and I'm convinced she's a killer guitarist, she is a genuine metal-head and the first female artist to get her own Ibanez signature guitar.  She played something from her album, and it was one of those moments when you realize how good someone is at guitar.  Without the help of studio backing, she nailed a wily solo without a hint of error.  Neato!\n\nAt the end of the session was the meet-and-greet, and she was signing stuff that people had brought.  I hadn't brought anything, but I was really feeling it at the end of the session, so I decided on the spur of the moment to buy something from the showroom real quick and have her autograph that.  I ended up picking this gorgeous sea foam green Ibanez S561.  When she saw it, she asked what the story was behind it, and I told her that I had just bought it, to be signed.  Her eyes popped out and she was counter-starstruck; she said if she had arrived earlier and seen it first, she would have bought it herself.  She hadn't seen it in that color and she loved it.  I was convinced she meant it because she held up the line to talk to me about it and turn it over in her hands admiring it.  We took a picture together, and the event coordinator gave me a free set of strings for being such a true fan, and I ended up getting a Nita Strauss signature guitar strap in gold and black (which incidentally matches my PRS, so it now lives with that guitar).  It was a really cool event over all and I'm super glad to have gone.\n\nRegarding the guitar itself, it's a Cor-Tek Indonesian-made model, and kinda feels like a weird mix of qualities: it's a budget guitar in the way it plays, though the feel of the materials and the fit and finish are excellent.  Very strange.  Might need to experiment with different strings on it."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Les Paul Clone",
    brand: "StewMac",
    year: "2021",
    imageFront: "lp-clone",
    imageBack: "lp-clone",
    history: "After a friend built me a guitar from scratch (see the Durazo Handmade), I got the idea to order a couple of kits and build them myself.  Not quite the same as building from raw blanks like Mr Durazo did, but still a significant endeavor, and required a fair bit of work in terms of assembly, preparing the wood, spraying the treatment, color, and finish on, electronics, and hardware installation, tuning, and set up.\n\nThis was the first kit I selected, a Les Paul style guitar from StewMac.  It came with red lacquer as a package, and I was happy with that.  The project was an experiment in going out of my comfort zone and taking risks with new challenges I hadn't attempted before.  For example, I remember the terror I felt when gluing the neck into place.  That is the kind of task that, if botched, is not easily undone - if at all.\n\nThe kit came with a completed neck, and all the wooden pieces pre-cut.  The first step was prepping the wood, which meant hours, and I mean *many* hours of sanding, followed by two rounds of wood grain filler, followed by yet more sanding, followed by grain sealer.  At last, the color could go on, and the red lacquer was surpassingly beautiful, highlighting the wood grain of the flame maple top.  Many layers of matte finish went on over the top of that, then the final hardware could be installed, and I tuned and set up the guitar and it plays (almost) like a dream.  My only complaints are that it turns out LP style guitars are not my favorite, as they aren't easily playable on the knee for taller folk like myself; and that I haven't found a perfect balance between string action and string buzz.  Other than that, it's actually one of the top quality guitars in my colleciton - I'm extremely proud of this project."
  },
  {
    type: "Acoustic",
    model: "1F-50CS",
    brand: "Tiny Boy",
    year: "Early 2000s",
    imageFront: "1f-50cs",
    imageBack: "1f-50cs",
    history: "I lived tucked away in a suburb of a suburb of Tokyo, Japan for a year in college, studing abroad.  At the time, I had no way to continue my guitar playing, since it was basically impossible to bring a guitar with me to Japan as a student.  For months I went without any guitar at all; but then, one fateful day, I was shopping in town with another ex-pat, and we stumbled across a budget musical instrument store.  Hanging there was a cheap-o, mini, short scale, steel string guitar: this Tiny Boy.  The fellow ex-pat (a girl, as will be important later in the story) saw me eyeing it, and recalling my woe of guitar withdrawal, simply bought it for me without asking!  A marvelous gift.  Days later, recounting the story among a larger group of friends, I suggested that she sign the guitar and leave a lipstick mark on it so I'd never forget where it came from.  She hesitated but ultimately agreed, as you can see in the picture!\n\nOnly later did I learn that she had a crush on me all along, and I had never figured it out.  Call me a late bloomer, an oblivious fool, I know not what college-me was thinking.  The guitar made it home to the United States, traveling in the care of a friend's brother, who had traveled to see that friend and myself in Tokyo, and I still have it to this day.  I've never gotten rid of it because I haven't had the heart, though it is, by some stretch, the worst-playing guitar in my collection."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "S-type Carbon",
    brand: "Partscaster",
    year: null,
    imageFront: "carbon",
    imageBack: "carbon",
    history: "In October 2022 I went on a road trip to Colorado to visit a friend.  I brought a guitar along (though I can't for the life of me recall if it was the Ibanez RG450 or the punked-out Squier) because this friend is also a guitar player, and is actually the owner of the PRS that made me decide *I* needed to have a PRS one day (which I now have).  We jammed one night during that trip, and while it was fun for me, I am not sure my amigo got the full enjoyment out of it.  In any case, this trip also happened to come not too long after a fateful road trip to Santa Barbara, on which I had purchased a cheap guitar to keep as a beater, which subsequently (and foolishly) convinced me that I needed to buy a cheap guitar on every road trip so that I could have a cheap collection of souvenir guitars.  This being the first road trip after that fateful SB road trip, I asked my friend if we could go visit a pawn shop in his town and see what they had.\n\nThey actually had a lot of really good guitars at that pawn shop, including a Gretsch and an Ibanez that were sadly quite a ways outside my price range.  What they did have, though, was this (sort of) incredible, hand made partscaster with a carbon fiber pick guard.  The piece of wood they chose for it is gorgeous and instead of painting or dyeing the guitar, they simply finished it in clear, so the wood's natural tone and grain are plain to see under the gloss finish.  It came with a broken nut, so I had to replace that (though I never glued it in place due to fear), and the pick guard's fit and finish are frankly atrocious.  It only plays... eh, alright I guess.  So I don't play it much.  It's on the short list to be sold, though I'm glad to have had a home for it for a little while."
  },
  {
    type: "Acoustic",
    model: "CS-6",
    brand: "Franciscan",
    year: null,
    imageFront: "cs-6",
    imageBack: "cs-6",
    history: "As the tale goes, my dad used to play guitar a bit.  He never took it very seriously, never knew too many songs, but he played, and the songs he played, he played well.  The way he tells it, he used to have a really nice classical guitar, but lent it to a cousin of mine, who proceeded to destroy it somehow.  By way of atonement, that cousin went to Mexico and bought my dad this Korean-made classical Franciscan as a replacement.  My dad never looked at any of the labels on the guitar and hilariously always thought it was a Mexican-made guitar.  Eventually my dad started getting a tremor later in life and decided that he couldn't play any more (thought he certainly could, and still does when I hand him the guitar, provided he's in a confident mood).  But regardless of what he *could* do, he threw in the towel and gave the guitar to me.  Now I play it, and continuously offer it back to him so he can play and keep the music in his fingers as long as he can.  As far as playability goes, I have never really tried another classical guitar out, so I can't say too much, though it is playable and I've learned a few songs on it.  The wide neck accommodating the nylon string set makes finger picking easier than on any of my other guitars.\n\nI remember taking this guitar to the beach one time on a date.  The girl was not impressed whatsoever, and never called me back again, and I got sand in the guitar, and I never brought a guitar to the beach again."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric Bass",
    model: "Squier P-BASS",
    brand: "Fender",
    year: "2004",
    imageFront: "p-bass",
    imageBack: "p-bass",
    history: "In October 2022 I went on a road trip to Colorado to visit a friend.  I brought a guitar along (though I can't for the life of me recall if it was the Ibanez RG450 or the punked-out Squier) because this friend is also a guitar player, and is actually the owner of the PRS that made me decide *I* needed to have a PRS one day (which I now have).  We jammed one night during that trip, and while it was fun for me, I am not sure my amigo got the full enjoyment out of it.  In any case, this trip also happened to come not too long after a fateful road trip to Santa Barbara, on which I had purchased a cheap guitar to keep as a beater, which subsequently (and foolishly) convinced me that I needed to buy a cheap guitar on every road trip so that I could have a cheap collection of souvenir guitars.  This being the first road trip after that fateful SB road trip, I asked my friend if we could go visit a pawn shop in his town and see what they had.\n\nOne thing they had was a bass that would become my first.  Despite being fully 18 years old, it was basically in new condition.  Shockinly pristine, essentially untouched, unplayed, no sign of use other than the sticker residue where the price tag from the pawn shop was placed.  To my surprise, this example was made by Cor-Tek, the same manufacturer that built my 2022 Ibanez S561.  I'm not a bass player so don't have anything to compare it to, but it feels extremely good, the fit and finish are perfect, and the materials are solid and lovely to behold and to the touch.  Hard to imagine wanting a \"better\" bass (unless you need more than 4 strings or a boatload of prestige)."
  },
  {
    type: "Acoustic",
    model: "S341",
    brand: "Sierra",
    year: null,
    imageFront: "s341",
    imageBack: "s341",
    history: "This acoustic was kind of a hand-me-down.  A girl I dated had it sitting in her dad's closet, disused, for 20 years.  She had gotten it as a gift in high school, hoping to learn to play, but never got around to it.  It sat and disintegrated until one day she gave it to me because she knew she was never going to use it.  This 7/8 size nylon acoustic was the first acoustic that I ever played seriously, and inspired me to learn to play (and minimally write) some basic blues songs.  I used to sit in her dad's house and play guitar and her family seemed to like listening to music coming out of those old guitars they had sitting around.  It came with some pretty well rotted strings, so my first task was to learn to install strings on a nylon-oriented guitar, but that was pretty easy and now it plays great.  The only thing that remains wrong with it is a slight bulge in the side wall of the body and you can feel the finish cracking over it."
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Bossman Blue Suede Shoes",
    brand: "Hardluck Kings",
    year: "2022",
    imageFront: "bossman",
    imageBack: "bossman",
    history: "An open-box find and impulse buy that in the end sadly didn't really fit in my collection."
  },
  {
    type: "Hollow-body",
    model: "ES-335 Clone",
    brand: "StewMac",
    year: "2021",
    imageFront: "mint-chip",
    imageBack: "mint-chip",
    history: "After a friend built me a guitar from scratch (see the Durazo Handmade), I got the idea to order a couple of kits and build them myself.  Not quite the same as building from raw blanks like Mr Durazo did, but still a significant endeavor, and required a fair bit of work in terms of assembly, preparing the wood, spraying the treatment, color, and finish on, electronics, and hardware installation, tuning, and set up.\n\n"
  },
  {
    type: "Electric",
    model: "Les Paul Clone",
    brand: "Grote",
    year: "2016",
    imageFront: "grote",
    imageBack: "grote",
    history: "An LP clone I bought at an auction in San Luis Obispo.  Chinese made but you'd never know it by playing it.  My best-playing LP clone (sad to say the one I built is not as good, but hey, I'm not a factory)."
  },
]
